KIKI HE

Detail-oriented multilingual data analyst with more than 5-year experience in Real Estate, Automotive, Finance, and Transportation. In addition to possessing solid backgrounds in data processing and analysis, web development, and project management, Kiki is a diligent team player with exceptional time management and multitasking skills.

SKILLS

- Proficient in SQL, Python, Tableau, Advanced VBA/Macro, and Microsoft Office Suite
- Experience in Axure, HTML, CSS, A/B testing, JavaScript
- Certficates: Google Analytics., Google Project Management
- Excellent in delivering complex concepts in a fair, concise, and lively manner, and adapting to change.
- Languages: English, French, Cantonese, and Mandarin

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Email Automation(Python) - Improve the operational efficiency by 90%

Designed and implemented email automation using Python that dynamically fetches data from databases and sends reports to stakeholders on a predetermined schedule. This automation resulted in a 90% reduction in manual effort required for monthly report distribution, ensuring timely and consistent communication of key metrics and insights.

Performance Dashboard (SQL) - Enhanced monthly reporting workflow with operational efficiency gains

Constructed a Mode Analytics dashboard that delivers comprehensive reports on ticket counts, SLA compliance by ticket type, and market-specific ticket performance, designed to facilitate data-centric discussions in monthly team meetings.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BI Analyst Lyft, Montreal QC

2022.05 – Current

- Dive deeply into extensive datasets to extract valuable insights using queries, thoroughly examine logs on SQL and Kibana to troubleshoot issues, identify root causes, locate pertinent documents for problem resolution, and develop SOPs to record new workflow.
- Utilize powerful data visualization tools such as Tableau and Mode to create dynamic and visually engaging data representations for stakeholder to comprehend and interact with the data, facilitating better-informed decision-making and team performance.
- Actively engage with cross-functional teams to monitor and manage the progress of critical issues, including understanding and documenting project workflows, ensuring alignment with project objectives, and fostering open communication to clarify expected outcomes.

Data Analyst Midea Group, Guangdong, China

2020.12 - 2022.02

- Critically evaluate information gathered from multiple sources and optimize the workflow by automating tasks
- Liaise with the R&D team in planning, developing, and implementing technology data platforms and projects
- Proactively collaborate with external and internal stakeholders to distinguish true needs from their requests and deliver actionable solutions or root-cause analysis case by case with support of SQL database, python, and Tableau
- Provide Business Requirements Document and Workflow Process Onboarding and conduct necessary operational tasks or performance review for the interns, including incentive programs, compensation statement, compliance, etc.
- Initiate regular meetings to track and review the progress of projects and identify possible obstacles and trend
- Monitor data quality by querying data to identify, investigate, and resolve data discrepancies or systematic error

Other positions: Financial Advisor Assistant, IT Support Assistant, Research Analyst

EDUCATION

Master of Information Concentrated in Data Science and UX Design, University of Toronto, ON
Diploma of Vocational Studies in Computing Support, Verdun Adult Career Center, QC
2022.09 – 2024.04
2017.12 – 2019.06

Relevant Courses: Systems Analysis (Database Management), Operating Systems, Researching Information

Bachelor of Arts in Double Majors: Communication and Linguistics, Simon Fraser University, BC 2014.01 – 2017.06